We will revisit the brain, this time integrating it with the heart and the circulatory system.
The mesenteric axis is the rotational axis for the development of my peritoneal framework.
It makes a downward movement, it comes back, I change, I try to tilt and
it comes in like this.
So ultimately, it creates a movement like that, like this.
The brain does this.
At the same time, I have this
at the same time I will have this
at the same time at the level of my kidneys
I will have this
at the level of my liver I will have this
Today we will review this motility
of brain development
and we will integrate it with what we have seen
on the cardiac level
And we will see how the heart supports brain development.
Don't forget, the heart can be seen in the yolk sac.
I take a reference which is my Louis angle,
because I know I’m in my second intercostal space.
I take my middle finger to go to the Louis angle,
I place my hand and align it with the heart, like this.
Easily, the heart is more in pronation, so in diastole.
So that means it is searching...
See? It is searching for something.
In the engagement of its life, it is a bit more withdrawn than
in its action.
I place myself here at the hepatic level.
You apply very little...
You know, like there’s an ant you can’t crush.
Now we wait.
I look at the liver because if it is a bit more horizontal,
that means the liver may be a bit swollen.
Does it change or not when we apply hepatically?
It tends to move this way.
Now, we will see here.
Here, at the kidney level, I take a kidney, it is more in pronation.
So, it tends more toward its lesion, so to speak.
So, what does this mean?
That it is more the kidney that destabilizes here.
Whereas the liver helps it.
Thus, we know that the kidney is related to emotional aspects, especially fear.
It is someone who will seek a point of support, but their point here is a story that is blocked.
So, with this gentleman, I work on his kidneys to support his heart.
that their embryonic movement, if I repeat, is a movement that does this
while the heart does this with this movement afterward
what do we do
I made an induction towards its pronation, or rather towards diastole
I support its kidneys, see what will happen, do you feel the difference?
it wants to reorganize itself independently
Because later, I will show you the motility of liver development, but with the vascular system.
We will also explore the motility of kidney development and how we can support it.
It is crucial to remember that the heart, in its form, is the result of the echo of its periphery.
That’s why there is all the pulsology which is really interesting.
We can feel if it’s a pulse that is more arterial in type
or a pulse that is venous with stasis.
For example here, it's a pulse...
To me, there are stasis occurring, probably in the hepatic area.
So, an arterial pulse, when you take it, is a pulse that is...
While a venous pulse is one that is more...
Nonetheless, it is on an artery that I feel this.
So, am I more in systole or in diastole, ultimately?